DANIEL MCINTYRE

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a front-end web developer utilizing my skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript frameworks to build the responsive and accessible websites and applications of tomorrow! My passion for finding solutions to problems as well as leading and managing teams is highlighted through my decade of experience in previous strategic communication-based roles.

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript ES9
- SASS
- React
- GitHub
- REST APIs

- Firebase
- Command line
- Organization
- Time Management
- Attention to detail
- · Critical thinking

- Team Building, Training and Development
- Communication
- Management
- Leadership
- Self-Motivated

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology, Toronto, ON

Immersive Certificate, Web Development Bootcamp, January 2022 – April 2022 Introduction to Web Development, November 2021 – December 2021 JavaScript Fundamentals, December 2021 – January 2022

University of Guelph, Guelph, ON Bachelor of Arts, Media Studies, 2008 - 2013

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

Video Diary

LIVE REPO

REST API | Firebase | React

Utilizes Youtube's REST API and firebase database to fetch and search videos based on the user's search query. Users can also save and delete their videos.

Giphy Sentiment

LIVE REPO

REST API | Firebase | React

Utilizes Giphy's API and firebase database to fetch and search Giphy's based on the user's search query. Users can also save their Giphy's.

Movie Mood

LIVE REPO

REST API | HTML | CSS

Utilizes the Movie Database (TMDB) API to fetch movies based on the selection of a movie genre and time-period.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

College of the Kinesiologists of Ontario, Manager of Communications May 2021 - October 2021

Managed all internal and external communications material and media, including website.

Grosso McCarthy Inc., Manager of Client Services, March 2016- December 2020

• Lead, trained and directed the Communications team and developed client proposals leading to acquisition of new clients for the firm.

Patients Canada, Manager of Communications, March 2016 – December 2020

 Responsible for the re-development of Patient's Canada's website, including implementing front and back-end features. Also managed the CiviCRM database system.

Office of the Federal Minister of Health, Communications Assistant, Sept 2014 – December 2015

Developed and executed media strategies, including implementing social media campaigns.